I don't think stable coin issuers are
going to make that much money. Stable
coins will be basically like a zero
margin product.
>> What else do you foresee in the future
that would be worth paying attention to?
>> The meta that's really starting to heat
up now is this a savings account that
pays you to 8 to 12% uh interest and
then a credit card that pays you 3% cash
back. That's crazily better than a
traditional bank. you got money from a
crypto exchange into your bank account
and like they would just turn your bank
account off. Every bank will have
[music] something like a bad news
division. So if you have an account with
a bank, they're looking at all all over
the internet. If your name pops up in a
bad newspaper article, it goes to the
compliance team and they review it and
if you do something bad, they'll just
turn stuff off. It's mostly theater.
It's supposed to prevent bad people from
using these financial systems. They
totally don't work.
Got the whole crypto world [singing]
going wild. [music]
[music]
Today's discussion is one I am very
excited for because this might be the
easiest way for you to experience what
the future of finance looks like. Um,
it's not about holding crypto anymore.
It is about being able to use it in your
everyday life. Buying that new iPhone,
buying groceries, or buying your mom
that new car she wants. There's no
better person to talk about this than
Mike. He is the founder of EtherFi.
Hello, Mike.
>> Hey, how's it going? Yeah, thanks for
having me.
>> I've heard this project a long, long
time ago from Arthur Hayes. He couldn't
stop talking about it. And now that
you're here, for people that are not
familiar with it, tell me what you do.
>> So, Ether's uh mission is to create a
full endto-end alternative to
traditional banking. So, uh if you've
used products like Revolute or Chime or
New Bank, EFI is building uh something
that is uh you know full endto-end
alternative to those types of products
and services.
>> And you want to be a bank. We want to,
you know, banks are a very specific type
of institution which take deposits. So,
Ether is non-custodial. So, we don't
take control over users assets. Um,
instead we give people all the same
services, all the same benefits like the
equivalent of a checking account, the
equivalent of an investing account, a
credit card that they can use to to
spend uh but while being non-custodial.
So the important part about that is that
uh we give people the ability to control
their their assets. So unlike a bank, we
don't you know we don't have the ability
to take your money. You know the
government can't come in and uh take
your wealth with Ether. You retain uh
custody. Plus we have much lower fees
and much higher rewards than you know a
traditional bank would provide.
>> A Treadfi person if they hear this
they'll be like oh two questions. One,
what is your business model then? If you
don't hold my money, second, where is my
money then? If I were to use the card,
then it has to go somewhere, right? It's
like a check checking or like a debit
card type of system.
>> Yeah. Well, so I mean this is the power
of crypto, right? Like when you think
about Bitcoin or or Ethereum or uh uh
you know, any other you know crypto
salana, whatever. Um the benefit is when
you have your crypto wallet whether it's
a hardware wallet or you know software
wallet on your computer when you deposit
Bitcoin or ETH or or stable coins into
it uh there is no third party uh that
holds custody of your assets. It's
actually it's self-custodial. So in
other words you as long as you can
remember the seed phrase to your uh your
wallet uh there's no way that you know
anybody can take uh uh those assets away
from you. So it's the same with Ether.
um when you deposit your ether your BTC
or your stable coins into EtherFi,
you're putting it into smart contracts
and you you are trusting the code in
those smart contracts. You don't have to
trust us as as Ether. Um now to your
other question, you know, how do we make
money? You know, interestingly, the
business model is actually very similar
to traditional banks. So, for example,
on the credit card side, every time that
you know you swipe uh your your Visa or
whatever credit card, the merchant, so
the store that you're buying your stuff
from pays usually around 3% of that
transaction to Visa and then Visa gives
us a slice of that. So, we make about
1%, you know, off of what that merchant
uh, you know, merchant pays. Um, uh, so
in other words, the user, the customer
doesn't pay anything. we're we're taking
it out of the share, you know, from the
uh the business. And then in addition to
that, if you use other parts of the E5
uh products like the DeFi strategy
vaults, then we charge a fee on those,
but that's completely transparent. It's
open. You know exactly how much it's
going to cost you. Uh you can see where
the assets are. Um uh and so in that
sense, I think it's uh it's a much more
democratic uh kind of system than
traditional finance.
>> Is it a credit card or a debit card? So
it is a credit card. Uh it it it's a
credit card in the sense that you can
borrow um and just the way that it's
it'ssued. Um it is a credit card. Uh but
for now all loans on the credit card are
fully collateralized. Uh so you need to
have assets like Bitcoin or ETH or
whatever uh that you're borrowing
against.
>> What is the endgame if it's the endgame
is a credit card, but how do you verify
my credit?
Yeah. So, well, because it's a credit
card, we do KYC. So, in other words, we
verify people's identity and you know,
uh collect information about them. Uh
and over time, you know, of course, we
get a lot of information about how much
income a person has and their spending
habits, their assets, you know, on
chain. Uh which I think makes it
possible for us to eventually give users
uh uncolateralized credit. So,
eventually we we plan to uh uh to be
able to do that. Uh but I think frankly
more interestingly um the long-term goal
is to completely get off of Trafi. Like
the long-term goal is to go directly to
merchants and bypass any of the you know
credit card networks and allow people to
directly pay uh you know for their stuff
using their crypto uh assets. Uh but
that's going to take time. you know,
that's a that's a huge initiative to be
able to turn uh turn those those rails
on for all the hundreds of millions of
merchants all around the world.
>> I think I've heard a lot of crypto
friends, they're like, "Yeah, well,
they're pretty wealthy, but they can't
really get the traditional credit card
because, you know, the the banks can't
really verify their assets." Now, from
what I've heard, you are trying to
verify their assets on chain. So let's
say I am a person that is rich in banks
in fiat. Now can you verify that in the
future?
>> Um not at this point. Uh I mean but it's
not hard to imagine you know a time in
the future where uh there's some sort of
oracle system that does allow you to you
know uh to actually verify people's
wealth uh you know offchain. You know
it's it's funny right cuz in in the
traditional world it's the you know the
problem is the exact opposite right? you
might have, you know, millions of
dollars of Bitcoin or ETH and the bank
doesn't recognize that at all. Um, but
it's it's not hard to imagine a time in
the future when you have the reverse
situation where the default is on chain,
but maybe you have uh you know some
stocks or whatever in your uh uh in your
investment account and uh you know like
your onchain credit program doesn't
recognize those. So yeah, it's
eventually might might come full circle.
What inspired you to start this? Is it
because you faced similar situations?
>> I mean, I got into Bitcoin pretty early.
Um, I read the white paper. Uh, I bought
some Bitcoin back in 2011. And so, when
uh when Bitcoin launched, like this idea
of a stateless money that was inflation
proof um and fully transparent uh um was
something that really appealed to me. Um
so um uh so this just aligns in my
values. I think this uh uh this uh next
generation financial system that is much
more transparent, much more fair, uh
much more democratic um is is something
that I think is an important way of
preserving and uh uh and increasing the
amount of economic freedom that exists
in the world.
>> But not everybody has this idea of what
they want the world to be. Like let's
say if I'm just just a regular crypto
holder, why do I need this card?
>> Uh well, so yeah, so as a product, this
is I would say it's the easiest way for
you to use your crypto in real life. So
if you have a bunch of crypto wealth,
>> you know, um most crypto people go
through this dance of all right, you
get, you know, hopefully you're you're
successful, you're, you know, number
goes up, uh you become wealthier, and
then every couple of months uh or so,
you take that money, you put it into an
exchange, maybe you sell it for fiat or
stable coins, then you send it to a
custodian, then send it to a traditional
bank, and then eventually now you can
use it in in real life. And it's a it's
a long it's a painful process. Um and
and at every stage you incur risk. Like
with Ether you skip all of that. You
basically you download the app,
>> you can get a credit card uh this this
credit card within 2 minutes you know
after you set up your account. Uh and
then you directly load it with fiat and
then just spend it in your real life. So
uh for me uh what that means is I
basically replaced probably 95% of my
banking uh with ether file cuz I can
deposit fiat if you receive fiat as a
salary if you want. You can deposit fiat
it automatically gets converted to
stables. I can you know deposit crypto
and use that in in my uh day-to-day. I
can send wire transfers if I need to. So
if I need to make payments uh uh or you
know pay for stuff in the real world, I
can just do that. It really does uh
replace uh remove the need for a
traditional bank uh as a user. And this
is especially true for people in um uh I
guess non US markets. Uh you know our
number one market right now actually is
in Brazil.
>> Uh that's like where most where many of
our users are. Uh another number two
market is actually Taiwan. Um so we're
seeing a lot of growth in markets where
people want these virtual US dollar bank
accounts uh that let them save, invest,
earn, spend uh all uh you know
seamlessly in crypto while maintaining
their wealth in uh you know in dollars
>> and it's all through an app. Is that
correct?
>> Correct. Yeah. Yeah. You can just
download the iOS app and go through the
whole process. Uh uh you know I think in
for many people they wouldn't even
necessarily even realize that they're
using crypto. like you just download an
app, you sign up, you can fund it with
with fiat. So like in Brazil, we just
introduced support for Pix, which is a
um like this uh the most the most widely
used payment system in Brazil that you
can pay your mortgage, you can pay your
rent, uh you can get paid uh your salary
through FIX. So, uh, for someone in
Brazil signing up, you know, creating
the account, like they wouldn't even
necessarily realize that they're using
crypto because you're just depositing
money and then you're spending and
investing it. Like the the crypto part
is completely abstracted. Uh, all that
complexity goes away. You just get the
benefits. I I think I've heard someone
like the first few times I've heard
about this project, people are talking
about it being a DeFi card and then at
the time I was like [clears throat] that
word is going to scare some people away.
>> But when I actually use it, there's it's
so easy to use. It just feels like the
traditional bank apps that you would
you're familiar with.
>> So
>> that's great. That's so awesome to hear.
I mean, I think
>> yeah,
>> uh there's still room to make it even
easier, but uh but that's great to hear
cuz that's exactly what we're going for
is just make it super easy for uh for
people.
>> Another thing that I love is the
transaction limit. You can just buy
something really really expensive
because back in the days, if you want to
buy something really expensive, you kind
of have to call your bank and be like,
"Hey, there's this really huge
transaction coming in, la." You have to
explain yourself. Now you don't. And
this is what I really love.
>> Yeah, for sure. I mean, we've had people
um I mean, people buy $100,000 watches.
We've had people buy cars. Uh we had
somebody pay $150,000 tax bill with the
card. Um somebody put a down payment on
a house with the card. Great. Yeah. Do
whatever.
>> Nice.
>> Do whatever you want. Yeah, it's it's
great.
>> And they get cash back on all these
transactions,
>> correct? Yeah. Uh so it's 3% cash back.
Uh basically no limit on uh uh on
anything that you buy.
>> That's crazy. If the purchase is big.
>> Yeah. So, you know, you buy $100,000
watch, you get $4,000 [laughter]
back.
>> By the way, really quick heads up.
Etheri is doing something special for
our community. If you sign up using our
link, you'll get $25 instantly. And Mike
was kind enough to give us access to
their new gold card program. The rewards
are honestly mind-blowing. We'll talk
about that in full details later, but
basically it is the first crypto card
that gives 4% cash back. So stick around
till the end. You'll definitely not want
to miss this.
There are some centralized exchange
cards out there and how is yours
different?
>> There are many many of these um
cryptoconnected cards uh out there. Um
uh without talking about specific ones,
uh most of them are really bad. I mean,
this is why none of them, like very few
other cryptocard programs have gotten
uh, you know, to any meaningful size
because they just they tend to be like
really bad products. Um, they're either
complicated to use or they have lots of
restrictions like they advertise, you
know, 4% cash back, but it's limited to
like a few hundred.
>> Um, or, you know, they advertise all
these benefits, but you have to use this
exchange which has like really crazy
fees in order to on ramp um and and
things like that. Uh but the other
benefit is as I said is etheri is
self-custodial. So if you're using
exchange cards you are you know you can
still be debanked your assets can still
be frozen your account can be locked
right which happens all the time with
many exchanges. Um uh whereas with
etheri I mean we can't lock your account
your assets are yours. Um if we don't
like what you're doing or whatever I
mean there's nothing we can do there
like you are actually retaining custody
of your asset. Uh which I think is
important. I mean, I think that um uh
you know, you can't get liquidated uh in
the way maybe uh you know, certain
exchanges have done recently. So, uh
yeah, it's it's it just gives you a lot
more control and uh and safety.
>> I think for people that haven't tried it
or are not familiar with how it works,
the question would be, well, I kind of
need money to be in the account to be
able to spend it right now. So, where
does that money go? Let's say I want to
put in $10,000 just in case I want to
spend. Where does that money go? When
you say it is still, you are still
holding it. What does that even mean?
>> So, it goes into a smart contract that
is controlled by your wallets. So, for
example, I mean, I don't know how
familiar uh your viewers, listeners are
with like other DeFi projects, but let's
say you put you take $10,000 uh in
stable coins or, you know, like you
know, five ETH in uh you know, in crypto
uh and you put it into, you know,
product like a right. Well, where that
those stable coins or that ETH is is in
a smart contract. It's not like Mr. a
can show up and just like pull your your
money like no you like you're trusting
the code that's uh that it's built on.
So in the exact same way you're putting
uh your money into smart contracts that
are controlled by your uh wallet. So
you're you're trusting the code. You're
not trusting any uh you know central
entity uh to uh to not take your uh you
know your money.
>> When I swiped a card, what really
happened behind the scene? Uh it's a
long and complicated process. [laughter]
Um there's I mean there's like six
different entities probably more
involved in every you know transaction.
Um so you know step one you know you
select the card the merchant um submits
a transaction to try and charge uh try
and charge you that goes to Visa that of
course verifies that the card you know
exists and is is valid. Um which then
eventually makes its way to our systems.
our systems look at your account uh and
determine like okay does this person
actually have enough money to be able to
to spend and then an onchain transaction
is submitted. So basically a you know
like in the same way that you send
Bitcoin or ETH or whatever an onchain
transaction is submitted that approves
that transaction you know on your uh uh
on your your smart contract safe and
then you know funds are deducted uh from
it and then eventually you know through
a series of steps that gets settled with
Visa and then Visa actually uh gives the
money to the uh uh the merchant. Um um
but um at any point you can withdraw all
of the funds from the the safe uh from
the from Ether or you can lock it down
and say okay I want I'm not allowing any
more uh spending on the uh the account.
So those transactions only go through
with your permission uh you know as long
as you're willing to uh you know to
allow the system to spend uh your money.
>> I heard this expert a stable coin expert
from Singapore. He was on a show and
then he was talking about how you know
stable coin is better than the
traditional fiat system because when you
pay when you pay there are two steps.
One is the communication between two
devices. One is the settlement and for
the traditional fiat system the
settlement is t plus however many days
and sometimes you know the merchants
have to wait for days to receive that
money
>> weeks or months. Yeah.
>> Right. Right. And for stable coins, they
just receive it right away because
communication is settlement,
>> which
is that happening right now because
we're still going through Visa.
>> Yeah, you're still going through Visa.
So, it's the same from the merchant
standpoint, they still have to wait
depending on, you know, jurisdiction and
how it's set up. They they might wait
days or weeks or or longer for the
transaction. So, this doesn't solve
that. This helps the user. it really
doesn't help the uh the merchant that's
a longer you know longer term uh
solution that needs to be uh needs to be
implemented
>> but in the ideal near future what would
it look like are we going to skip Visa
Masterard
>> yeah and look maybe though not maybe I'm
sure they're going to look at their
networks and you know upgrade them to
support um
>> uh you know stable coin uh transfers and
you know have these reduced fee uh
models so uh for sure that's uh you know
that that's going to happen. It's not
going to be on the current kind of
rails. Um like Visa does useful things,
right? Um there's fraud protection,
right? Um there's things like
chargebacks, there's, you know, there's
a lot of work that goes into there's
verifying merchants so that you don't
have somebody gets your credit card
number, they can just take all your
money, right? like there's a lot of
protections behind the scenes that are
are valuable and all of that stuff needs
to needs to be built right on chain
before you can completely uh you know uh
go direct uh to a merchant. Um so you
know it sounds simple um in a sense this
transaction like you you go to whatever
an online merchant you buy something and
yeah they get the money instantly but
like you know think about what that
means that means you can't reverse the
transaction it means there's uh you know
less fraud protection so uh it's not as
as simple as it sounds um uh there's
>> but is that the end game or is that just
a fantasy world?
Certainly, it'll reduce fees when you
have an endto-end crypto stable coin
system. It'll reduce fees uh quite a
bit, but you know, it's not going to be
zero, but like yeah, maybe it'll make
them uh you know, 80% uh lower. Uh
certainly it'll make settlements, you
know, to some degree faster and more
transparent. Um so, so yeah, it'll be
it'll be better. And even today like
just on the consumer side and the
customer side someone using the etherfy
product the user is already getting a
huge benefit. Um the benefit they're
getting is uh you know one I mean
obviously we talked about sort of uh the
self- custody aspect of it but they also
just get much much higher rewards on
their asset right if you deposit your
your assets into etheri on US dollars uh
you know
this isn't a forward-looking projection
but historically users would have gotten
you know 8 to 12% interest on their on
their dollars. So, it's um analogous to
a savings account that pays you 8 to 10%
to 8 to 12% interest and then a credit
card that pays you 3% cash back. Like
that's a that's crazily better than a
traditional bank, right? Like I don't
know what your bank pays you. I don't
even know what interest rate it is, but
I mean it's basically
>> it's so little I I don't even know.
>> That's right. Yeah, it's basically zero.
And you know, I don't know any credit
card that pays you 3%. So just on that
aspect of it, there's a huge uh you know
a huge benefit to uh to users.
>> Where did that 8 to 12% come from?
>> So it comes from DeFi. Um
>> lots of different steps, but mostly it's
like lending and token rewards. So
mostly you're lending out your dollars
to people who, you know, want to borrow
them and uh and you're getting token
rewards from various uh uh partner
protocols. So if I need money, I can do
the same thing on Etherfy and lend
money.
>> Uh well, so it's indirect and I'm just
saying you're depositing dollars into
Ether and then you put it into our
>> DeFi vaults which earn, you know,
whatever the interest rate is these
days.
>> Um where that interest comes from is
usually it puts it into various DeFi
protocols which are in most cases
various forms of lending. Right.
>> So there's no mystery about like where
does the yield come from? It's it comes
from lending for the most part.
>> For users, what type of assets can be
spent? Is it USDC only or other assets
as well?
>> So you can deposit uh USDC, USDT or
these liquid strategy vaults. And you
can also spend those assets. So this is
the cool thing is you can hold your
assets within DeFi and then actually
spend it directly from there. So you
don't need to do any complicated stuff
with kind of like unwrapping,
withdrawing, whatever. It's just it's
all kind of abstracted from you. So you
can do something as simple as just put
in USDC and spend that
>> or put it into this, you know, DeFi
strategy vaults that gives you some
rewards and then spend that directly
>> and the rest will still be generating
yield or
>> correct. Yeah. So, your entire account
balance could be generating DeFi yields
uh and then you you know you sort of
spend that as you go or you can borrow
against it. That's what a lot of people
do.
>> Earlier you talked about depositing US
dollars. So, if I am using a Taiwanese
bank or any Asian banks, can I actually
deposit fiat or USD into Etherfy and
start spending there? If you support uh
Swift or AC or Aduire or SEPHA I think
um uh which most international banks do
support if you can wire money into a US
dollar account then yes you can uh you
can do that. So yeah you can wire money
from Hong Kong or Taiwan or whatever
that's it'll work fine.
>> It shows up usually within like a couple
of hours
>> and it shows up as USD or USDC USDT
>> USDC. So it automatically one to one
gets converted into stable coins. So you
don't even need to think about the you
know any of the intermediary.
>> I want to talk about Visa card and
Mastercard. So they they process more
than I think 14 trillion a year and they
take about you know 1 to 3%. Is that
correct? Yeah, I mean Visa takes um
uh you know there's lots of
intermediaries involved, right? There's
like like the issuing banks, uh there's
partners, there's uh uh transaction, you
know, payment processors and so on.
Yeah, I think Visa would say maybe a
little less than 1% of the transaction
value. Amazon did around I think 600
billion in revenue and pays let's say 2%
in card fees and that's about 12 billion
a year. This number comes from last
year. So I think a lot of these retail
giants they're you know considering
building their own stable coin in
private blockchains because they want to
save on these fees. Mhm.
>> Um what what do you think the trend is
from you know an expert's perspective?
Do you think these big companies will
start creating um stable coin systems of
of their own and then you know kind of
trap the funds within their own
ecosystem. For example, if you're a
partner that you know gets paid, then
you can spend that stable coin within
that within that ecosystem on let's say
uh cloud service or other services.
>> It's not hard to imagine a world where
there's you know thousands of these
stable coins that uh uh you know every
merchant has their own f different
variation of it. Um uh but it's also not
hard to imagine uh most merchants just
choosing to use a third party option
because they can still save that you
know 2 to 3% that they pay on merchant
fees um uh by using a third party stable
coin. I mean the thing with stable coins
is everyone's very excited about uh you
know these trillions of dollars that are
going to be minted in in stable coins.
Um they but like running a stable coin
is actually not going to be a very good
business because like you're going to be
the expectation will be that all of the
guo the underlying you know treasury
bill yo just gets passed on to
customers. So it very quickly is going
to be a business that approaches you
know sort of zero margin. Um so
>> are we talking about the issuer
>> the issuer of the stable coin? Yeah. So
are, you know, is Amazon or others or
Walmart or whatever going to issue their
own stable coin?
>> Like maybe that's possible. Like maybe
they can, you know, get users to hold a
balance with them, right? Uh we've seen
that from places like Starbucks, right?
They have their Starbucks app and gift
cards that you can, you know, preload
and spend and they have billions of
dollars of uh customer deposits which
are earning no interest for their their
customers. Um, uh, but like it's also
hard for me to imagine, you know, users
holding a balance with like with Amazon,
with Walmart, with Costco, with
whatever. Like, are you really going to
hold balances across all of these
different merchants? Like, probably not.
So um are these merchants then going to
you know get much of a benefit from
issuing their own stable coin versus
just using a third party uh whether it's
Circle or you know or somebody else um
using a third party stable coin and uh
not really worrying about it too much
because what I was trying to say is I
don't think stable coin issuers are
going to make that much money because
the expectation is going to be
>> yeah that you pass all of that yield on
to your users
>> and so stable coins will be basically
like a zero margin uh product. So, I
don't know that Amazon is going to be
too excited about issuing their own
stable coin, but I do think you know
what we talked about earlier um uh you
know a lot of these payment networks
transitioning to just direct stable coin
payments. I think that's uh you know
very reasonable because then yeah it
saves the merchant you know 2 to 3% on
their transactions.
regarding what you just said uh but
issuers like USDC USDT they are probably
some of the most profitable companies in
the world so that is
>> today
>> right now and but later on you foresee
that they're going to have less uh
revenue
>> well first of all like falling interest
rates as interest rates fall um you know
their revenue goes down like directly um
but then in addition to falling interest
rates the expectation will be that they
pass on all of that interest to their
their users. Um that's not, you know,
today, maybe not even in in a year, but
um that's the end game, right? It's like
that's just
>> that's just going to be the default. Uh
>> so, okay. The Genius Act actually says
issuers cannot pass on the yield to
users, but I I assume what you're saying
is they're going to look for other ways.
Yeah, there's most uh of these uh
alternative stable coins find ways of
passing that yo to users indirectly like
um I mean there's different ways of of
doing it. Maybe the user stakes the
stable coin and then part of staking it
is you get a reward that just you know
happens to be exactly the same as the
you know the treasury built yield or
even a little bit higher, right? We see
most new stable coin entrance uh
boosting the reward. So they're actually
paying out more than you know the
interest that they're collecting in
order to get um um you know adoption. So
it actually becomes a loss leader in in
many cases. So, um, yeah, so there's
there's lots of loopholes that, you
know, that allow stable coin issuers to
pay out that yield to users. This is
really interesting because I went on a
few interviews like local interviews and
they were asking these are um like
brokers and more traditional finance
people and they're interested in
investing in stable coin related stock
or other you [clears throat] know things
but
>> right now there are only a few like it's
very clear that it's only like oh circle
IPOed and all that
>> but Um, what else do you foresee in the
future that would be worth paying
attention to?
>> Yeah, so uh I think uh the meta that's
really starting to heat up now is this
category called crypto neo bankanks.
Kind of like like EtherFi. We're now
seeing a number of these projects
getting launched uh seemingly almost
almost daily. Um and to me that's a much
more um interesting business than just
stable coin issuers which again is I I
think over time is just going to get
commoditized and you know and the
margins end up going to zero pretty
quickly. Um um so whereas something like
a crypto neo bank um is much more of
like a picks and shovels play on stable
coins in that there's a revenue model,
there's users, there's distribution,
there's all all kinds of ancillary
sources of revenue that um uh you know
products like Ether have that don't just
rely on uh you know issuing the uh the
stable coin. So Ether generates revenue
from all transactions. So we take
roughly 1% of interchange revenue from
the merchant that we you know we talked
about earlier. Uh we generate some
returns if users are borrowing against
their assets. So we take a spread on
that. Uh if users are doing swaps within
the app, uh there's some revenue that
comes from that. Um if users are
depositing into DeFi into these strategy
vaults, there's a bit of revenue that
ETFy generates off of that. And then in
turn, uh staking uh rewards. So if
you're staking your ETH, your BTC, Ether
Fred generates some revenue there. And
soon um we're going to be launching
something called Ether Trade within the
app uh that allows you to actually trade
per uh you know using Hyperlid. So so
there's these there's a much more
broadly diversified uh revenue business
uh you know in Ether than just the um uh
you know the stable coin side of it.
>> So what else what else can I do on
Ether? Let's say let's say I think ETH
is going up and I don't want to sell it
but I need the money so I can just
borrow against my ETH. Is that correct?
>> Yeah, exactly. Yeah, that's a pretty
common thing that people uh do. Are
>> are people doing that now or do they
think E is going out?
>> Yeah, [laughter]
I mean look long term I think it's it's
a good bet. But yes, lots of people are
doing that.
>> Okay. And um a question more a little
bit more on you know the traditional
network and uh also stable coin swift
has been around forever and you know
this is how banks move money across
borders it's kind of slow and it's
pretty expensive but do you think stable
coin is starting to chip away that you
know swift's influence and maybe
completely in the future if that is the
case
>> does that mean
>> I mean not yet cuz the numbers are just
very small uh relative to you know all
of uh uh Swift volume but but eventually
of course yeah I mean it's just it's so
much better uh I mean it's so it's it's
obviously a superior model
>> but
like for example US if they want to
sanction other countries they kind of
use this system and that means in the
future if Swift's influence is being
weakened then you know this method you
can't really do that anymore I mean, in
some ways, it's actually much easier to
to do those kind of sanctions. Look, if
you're using US dollars, the the US
government can uh uh can get you. So, um
you know, as an individual user and you
have to
>> to get OFAC sanctioned is like, you
know, you have to be doing some bad
stuff. Uh but if you're you know, a
country or a bank and the US wants to
sanction you, it's actually very easy to
do that with the with stable coins. any
country stable coin should the
government be allowed to you know tell
the issuer who should we sanction and
who should we debank
>> uh it's not a question of like should or
shouldn't that that's just the reality
of it I mean as long as you're using
>> if you fully want to get off the you
know trady system you shouldn't be using
dollars if you're using something like
etheri you're not going to get debanked
or it's extremely like [laughter] the
threshold for you to get debanked is
very high. Like you have to like finance
North Korea or something or you know or
terrorism.
>> Okay, then you know we're going to have
to you know respect sanctions against
you or whatever.
>> Um but that's a very different threshold
than you send money to you donate money
to the wrong cause and your bank
suddenly says, "Ah, we're shutting off
your bank account."
>> Right. Which happens all the time.
>> Really?
>> Of course. Yeah. Of course. I mean um I
mean that happens uh you know all the
time. I mean it could be as simple as
you know at least doesn't happen anymore
with you know the Trump administration
but uh I mean honestly it was before
that I mean it was as simple as like you
got money from an from a crypto exchange
into your bank account.
>> True.
>> And like they would just turn your bank
account off or in you know in Canada I
lived in Canada for many years. Uh there
was during COVID uh like this big
protest that happened uh Canadian
truckers
>> uh were protesting COVID restrictions
and anybody that donated money to the
Canadian truckers uh ended up having
their bank accounts shut off.
>> That's insane.
>> Um yeah, I mean I had friends that, you
know, there's they'd been banking, you
know, with uh with some of the larger
banks for years, decades, and then they
just got completely shut off because
they, you know, sent them a few hundred
bucks. Um, so yeah, I mean this is a
this this happened all the time uh to
people. So th those types of things um I
can almost guarantee I mean they've
never happened to anybody with Ether Fi
because it's just yeah it's again the
threshold for getting like sanctioned
where like your you know your your
wallet addresses and you know identity
is blocked is is much much higher um uh
than like you know just some bank saying
we don't like this news article about
you so we're going to turn everything
off uh for you. So um you know most
people don't realize when um
um like every financial institution,
every bank, every yeah basically every
regulated financial institution um has a
you know an entire department dedicated
to compliance. Compliance basically is
like obeying all the regulatory laws
that are out there. And one of those
things is called uh like every bank will
have what's what's called something like
a bad news division. like literally
they'll have a a bad news division and
so they look for like articles online on
you know in like major publications and
they search for your name. So, if you
have an account with a bank, they're
looking at all all over the internet
with, you know, for articles and news
about your name and if your name pops up
in a bad newspaper article, it goes to
the compliance team and they review it
and they say, "Oh, Bob here, you know,
like did something bad like some, you
know, bad news. Okay, let's shut off all
his bank accounts because we don't want
to be associated with with Bob anymore."
This is this is it's I mean it's such a
dystopian thing. I mean this people
criticize you know China with their
social credit system like the same
exists in in North America like every
bank as they said has this division that
searches your name all over the internet
and if you do something bad they'll just
turn stuff off. Um
>> uh so that's the kind of stuff that this
um you know crypto neoanking
alternatives um help prevent in addition
to
not being able to just lock your bank
account, right? Like that's the other
okay like the bank can turn off your
your bank, but they can also lock your
money for whatever reason and then you
can't access it for uh you know for
years. Uh they can also gamble with all
of your money and then if they lose it
then you're screwed um and the bank
usually gets uh you know bailed out um
uh without any kind of transparency
existing around that. So those are the
things that uh this alternative system
can help uh prevent.
>> You don't have a bad news department.
>> We no we don't uh we do have a
compliance department unfortunately like
that we we're subject to um
>> to all the same kind of laws but it's
not you know it's not the same kind of
like uh you know dystopian thing.
>> I think it's comforting for most people
to know that you know the company is
compliant. And I I guess that's like the
basic, you know, people want to be able
to trust that whoever that's processing
their money is following the rules.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's mostly um uh
well, yeah, it's mostly theater, but uh
theater in the sense that it's supposed
to prevent
um you know, bad people from, you know,
using these financial systems. like
that's what the AML anti-moneyaundering
and KYC, you know, your your customer uh
laws are supposed to do. And they
totally don't work. I mean, they don't
prevent [laughter] any of that. All they
do is impose just a huge costs and
burden and create a bit of this like
surveillance state for normal people.
Um, you know, it's a little bit like the
TSA after 9/11. Uh, like it's just
mostly security theater. It doesn't
actually make anybody uh safer. So what
you're saying is people who want to do
bad things can actually go around it
easily.
>> The traditional systems. Yeah, of
course. I mean what
uh you know bad people have bank
accounts
>> and launder money all the time. It's not
uh it's not particularly difficult.
>> What's a better system then?
>> Well, the better system is presumption
of innocence. like you let people uh
engage in
>> in commerce and if they do something bad
then you can go in and do you know
investigations and uh
>> uh you know try and uh you know freeze
people's assets um
>> you know if if it's needed but like you
you have to have evidence like you have
to actually you know start with proof
that the person did something bad not
sort of uh you know impose this sort of
preemptive uh system of you know,
penalties and controls on on everyone.
Um, with the hope that maybe you'll
prevent some bad people from doing
stuff, but the reality that it doesn't
actually do any of that.
>> In in practice, what would that look
like? So, you still do KYC, but then
I think the problem is KYC. The process
is expensive. Is that what you're
saying?
>> I mean, you know, that's a that's a big
question like what does a, [laughter]
you know, better system look like? Um in
a sense for a very uh you know a lot of
the history of of finance when people
transacted with bearer assets or or cash
um you know there's no KYC when you do a
cash transaction right with with people
um so
um
that that's in many ways what crypto is
kind of going back to right going back
to bare assets where if you have a
wallet If you have assets in that wallet
that you can control, they're yours. I
mean, there's no nobody KYC, you know,
which Bitcoin address has which, you
know, how much, you know, Bitcoin. Um,
so going back to that kind of system, I
I don't know how much you actually lose
as far as protections. Uh,
>> I think, as I was saying, I think most
of those protections that exist today
are kind of theater. So you need to
identify a person who did something bad
and then
>> do investigations and identify, okay,
this is the address where the bad thing
happened and then try and figure out how
to restrict the movement of those those
assets.
>> Mike, I really enjoy this conversation.
It's not just about Ether. It's about,
you know, the future of money and also
stable coin and I think a lot of, you
know, thoughts that are deeper than just
money. So, I I really enjoyed it. And if
people want to sign up, you can use the
link down below. And if you refer
friends, there's a program for you. You
can get bonus and uh rewards and stuff.
Uh lastly, I would love to have you back
in the future if you'd like. And thank
you so much for your time.
>> Yeah, great great to be here. Great to
great chatting with you. I agree. It was
a great conversation.
>> Before we wrap up, here's something you
will want to know. Ether just launched a
gold card and there are only 30 cards in
the world. Off camera, Mike actually
told me he's giving five to our
community, which is huge. If you want
one, now's the time. Use the link down
below to sign up and start spending.
You'll get $25 instantly. And top three
spenders will be invited to become gold
card members and we'll draw two more
winners before Black Friday. So, you can
actually use the card for your holiday
shopping and get your 4% cash back on
everything, 5% on travel, up to 60% off
hotels, plus exclusive concierge, VC
investment access, and even direct
contact with the EtherFi leadership
team. If you don't make the gold card
list, you still get 3% cash back. So,
way above normal cards. I've got plenty
of shopping to do. So, if I'm spending
anyway, I want to get paid for it. Okay?
But just remember, this is DeFi and DeFi
products have risks just like any other
financial product. For spending, only
keep what you plan to use. If you're
going to try staking or borrowing,
definitely do your research first. Only
30 gold card exist and we've got five.
Check the description. and claim your
$25 and get your card before Black
Friday and Christmas hit to earn that 4%
cash back. Thank you very much, Mike.